JAKOB I FVFII I F

🛮 416-268-7793 | 🗷 hi@jakobleveille.ca | 😭 jakobleveille.ca | 🛅 jakobleveille

About me

A University of Waterloo graduate with a passion for community, climate, and creating. A background in biotechnology, paired with experience in internal and customer-facing roles across various industries, including transportation, finance, pharmaceuticals, and entrepreneurship. Currently exploring hardware/software and community-based projects, and highly interested in the venture capital/startup ecosystem.

Work Experience _____

Montere Waterloo, ON

Co-founder/CEO

Nov 2023 - May 2024

- Helped build a prototype modular and customizable at-home espresso machine, designed UX flows, and created logo and branding.
- · Conducted 50+ customer interviews, both in-person and virtually, alongside a survey with 100+ responses.
- Partnered with local cafes and an coffee machine repair shop to better understand processes, workflows and common issues.
- · Worked with Velocity incubator on campus, and was selected to move into their office for a pilot program.

Roche Mississauga, ON

Business Analyst

Sept 2021 - Dec 2021, Jan 2023 - Aug 2023

- Assisted in the development of the companies first Responsible Artificial Intelligence Policy through interviews, market research, surveys, presentations, and talks, which became a pillar of their core policies.
- Initiated and Facilitated a restructuring and merger of the Informatics Co-Op Program.
- · Led an internal employee engagement initiative through working with colleagues and external charities.
- Created and designed videos, user testing/wireframes, websites, and infographics for internal stakeholders.

MCAP Waterloo, ON

Business Analyst May 2022 - Aug 2022 · Used HTML to design and edit mortgage documents based on customer and legal guidelines to increase generation efficiency.

• Developed new templates, documentation, and SOPs to be implemented company wide.

Traffic Tech Mississauga, ON

Logistics Coordinator

Jan 2021 - April 2021

- Consistently finished top 3 company wide in customer connections made every week.
- · Negotiated rates and times with shippers and carriers, and created company-wide SOP's.

Education

University of Waterloo Waterloo, ON

BSc in Science and Business Co-op, Biotechnology Specialization

Sept 2019 - May 2024

- Founders Circle: Program for founders in Science and Business developed ideas, pitches, business plans, etc.
- Entrepreneurs in Science: Talks about the Waterloo ecosystem and my entrepreneurial journey to younger Science and Business Students.
- Fusion Conference: Case/Pitch competition for Science students, placed 2nd overall.
- · Science and Business Students association (SBSA): Event idea generation, planning, and logistics for Scbus Students.

Projects

SAM Waterloo, ON

Protyping Stage

June 2024 - Present

- · Building a solar-powered air quality monitor for homes to unlock insights about the conditions, quality, and trends of your living and sleeping environment using an ESP32 micro-controller and a SCD41 sensor.
- Building over 6 weeks for Buildspace Nights and Weekends Season 5.

The Kitchen Kitchener, ON

Communitech/Socratica

June 2024 - Present

- Running a free, daily co-working space for students and new grads working on passion projects over the summer.
- Building Partner relationships, running events, obtaining funding, and organizing with stakeholders.

Skills

Technical Basic Javascript/Python/R, Figma, Notion, Microsoft/Google Suite, Adobe Suite (Photoshop, Premiere Pro, Audition), Agile/Scrum.

Languages French (Conversational), English (Native).